我們這個月2021,我們在說一個系列,你知道這個系列叫什麼名字嗎?
Identity
是的,Identity and Relationship,今天很有參與力,這麼好
然後我們開始的時候,我們就說我們的身份在哪裡?
在神那裡,我們是在祂的形象中製造的
然後我們Pastor Gavin就和我們分享,我們的新的身份在於耶穌,因為我們接受了主耶穌,就有一個新的身份
然後我們就學了,我們是神的兒女,然後上個星期Pastor Irene幫我們說,我們的回應是什麼?我們怎麼可以做一個真實的,我們怎麼可以真實的對自己
然後今天我們就會說我們的回應,我們怎麼可以真實在我們的關係中
我們這個世界有很多東西是真實的對假的,你覺得有什麼是真實的對假的呢?
我有三個例子
人和人之間的真實與假的朋友
這個世界有很多東西是假的,很多假的手袋,很多假的鞋子,在女人街可以找到很多假的東西
現在很多人都有假錢,假金錢
這個面膜是什麼?
是不是forgery?
很多人都是fake的,他放了面膜,有些人對你前面是很好的,但在你背後就說很多壞話
有些人是fake,他說很想和你玩,很想和你打球,然後就不理你
有沒有人是有這樣的朋友?
我有
我有一個朋友就是去年和前年都是欺負我的
然後無端端在七年級的中間的時候,突然間進我的群組,對我很好
今天我們讀一個passage
(文字上的文字不太好,請看影片資訊欄)
今天我們讀這個passage,會看到Samuel如何變成一個真正的人,和神如何保持他的真正的保證
第一個point,我們看到Samuel overcome the disappointment of the rejection of Saul as king
你們知不知道以色列第一個王是誰?
他的名字叫做Saul,是很高大的
聖經說他是head above everybody else
one head above everybody else
當然沒有姚明那麼高,姚明是七尺三或七尺四
He is head above everybody else
我們看第一個point,是Saul overcome the disappointment of rejection
他做high priest是第一個去annoy Saul
他很傷心,因為Saul去disobey God
他就recognize他自己有一個right time
神就跟他說有一個right time
有一個right time to mourn,有一個right time to get up and anoint the next king
神就跟他說,How long will you grieve over Saul since I have rejected him over Israel?
Fill your horn with oil and go
神就跟他說,Fill your horn with oil,你會去go and anoint the next king
我們做一個real person,跟我們的friend的時候
我們都要recognize我們每個人都有一個right time
有時我們會sad,有時我們會happy
有時我們是要主動去做動作
我們看下一個point,是Samuel is sent to Jesse of Bethlehem, the grandson of Ruth and Boaz
我們看到神保持他的right promise
神的promise就是,1st Abraham會有descendants as numerous as the stars
他的line是繼續去through Ruth,跟著去through Jesse
所以我們看到神保持他的covenant,他的ultimate promise
我們做一個real friend,都要保持我們的promise
Next, Samuel fears Saul when asked to follow God's plan
你可能看到很多古代的故事
如果你去anoint another king,會怎樣?
王會accuse you of treason,很嚴重的
可能有punishment,major punishment,可能是death
Samuel跟神說,我怎可以去anoint another king?
現在是king,他聽到我去anoint一個king,就會想去追我
神怎樣comfort他?神跟他說,I will show you what you shall do
是不是很comforting?
Among fear,我們害怕的時候,神有沒有跟你說,I will show you what you will do
Samuel就place他的right fear給誰?
他的fear不是Saul,他的fear是towards obeying God
Ok, next slide
God rules Israel even though his people rejected him as king
The right authority
我們做一個real person的時候,我們都要recognize
我們的real right authority,real authority在哪裏?
我們的real authority是from 神
以色列是reject神,是king
他們說,這個nation有king,那個nation有king,我們都想要個king
我們不想一個invisible king,我們想要一個real king,一個人是king
但是ultimately,誰anoint那個king?
是God anointed that king
ultimately, he had the authority to anoint the king
Ok,我們繼續看Samuel 16:6-10
When they came, he looked at Elib and thought
Ok, Samuel去探了Jesse
跟著跟Jesse說,你是不是有很多子女?
你可不可以邀請你的子女給我?
我會anoint一個king from 你的子女那裏
第一個子女是誰?
Elib, and thought, he looked at Elib and thought
Surely the Lord's anointed is before him
But the Lord said to Samuel, do not look at his appearance or on the height of his stature
Because I have rejected him
For the Lord sees not a man's appearance
Man looks on the outward appearance
The Lord looks at the heart
Then Jesse called Abin-Abdab
And made him pass before Samuel
And he said, neither has the Lord chosen this one
Then Jesse made Shammath pass by
And Jesse made seven of his sons pass before Samuel
And Samuel said to Jesse, the Lord has not chosen these
Then Samuel said to Jesse, are all these your sons here?
And Jesse said, there remains one, the youngest
But behold, he is keeping the sheep
And Samuel said to Jesse, send and get him
For we will not sit down until he comes
And he sent and brought him in
Now he was rugged and had beautiful eyes and was handsome
And the Lord said, arise, anoint him, for this is he
And Samuel took the horns of oil and anointed him, poured oil on him
And made him, anointed him in the midst of his brothers
And the Spirit of the Lord rushed upon David from that day forward
OK, we see many different points here
First, Samuel is held back by his own perception of others
He sees the first son, how is the first son?
He is tall and looks like a king
But what does the Lord say to him?
Do not look at his appearance of his height and his stature
For I have rejected him as king
神很清楚地跟Samuel說
不要有你自己的perception做一個barrier
我們很多時候看到人就有一個perception
他是什麼人,他是什麼人,他好像怎樣
我們有時候看外表
但神說什麼?
Man looks at the outward appearance
But the Lord looks at the heart
神是看我們的心
God looks at the heart
如果我們有一個real relationship
我們要有一個right perception of others
我們要看我們身邊的人
as how God looks at them
We have to see people as how God looks at them
第二,我們看Samuel finds the right son
有多少個兒子?
Jesse有多少個兒子?
有七個兒子
然後他和Jesse說
這是不是你的所有兒子?
It's not all his sons
是Jesse還有一個兒子叫David
為什麼這麼有趣?
他不讓Jesse派出來給Samuel看?
因為Jesse had the wrong judgment of David
他小看了David
他覺得David最小的兒子
他可能十二、十三歲
很多人都是十二、十三歲
就可能看他還沒有準備好
他可能還沒有King的外表
Jesse的爸爸可能給了一個錯誤的判斷
對他的兒子David
但是Samuel看到他就說
Samuel就說
Is this your son?
This is his son
Arise!神就說Arise! Anoint him!
For this is he
Samuel anoints David as King
The right choice
對的選擇
God said
Now he was rugged and beautiful
had beautiful eyes and was handsome
Arise! Anoint him! For this is he
神就Anoint the right King
David
我們看到聖經
David是a man after God's heart
David是什麼王?
He is mentioned more than a thousand times in the Bible
他是一個one of the most popular kings
He wrote the psalms
撕篇
He poured out his heart
在不同的撕篇去解釋他的feeling towards God
很多的祈禱
今天我們看到這個故事
How to be real in our relationships
Samuel我們看到第一就是right time
Samuel看到他有一個right time
有時要mourn的
有時要開心的
有時要主動去跟隨神
The right promise
The right fear
The right authority
The right perception of others
The right judgment of others
有時我們會有一個wrong judgment
好像Jesse對他的youngest son David
然後我們要make a right choice
Ok next slide我們看到
我們要characterize
第一
If we are to be real
我們要有一個right foundation
我們的right authority
應該是recognize
神是我們的right authority
He is 去創造我們的
他是in control的
然後我們要有一個right fear
The right fear is that
we need to fear the Lord most of all
然後我們要understand ourselves
We need to understand ourselves
我們要有一個right perception of ourselves
Samuel的perception
第一個兒子就說
這麼高大這麼偉大
他應該是做王的
但神就說No
God looks at the heart
我們都要有一個right perception of ourselves
我們學了
We are made in God's image
Pastor Gavin解釋給我們聽
我們的identity is found in Christ
我們要有一個right perception of ourselves
If we are to have right real relationships
然後我們都要有right timing
我們要understand我們自己
有時我們是有up and down的
我們不用去be fake的
We need to be real
with ourselves and with others
第三就要treat others in a real way
我們怎樣可以treat others in a real way呢
我們要有一個right promise
The right promise
We need to be right promise
with honesty and with good character
我們怎樣可以做一個real friend
一個real person呢
我們要have right promises
Don't have lies, right promises
我們看人都要有一個right judgment
We need to see others as God sees them
然後我們要做對的選擇
We need to make right choices
when we are with our friends
我們和我們的朋友是要做對的選擇
我們要有愛心去愛他們
As God loves them
我show you a diagram
我快完結了
As we know ourselves more
我們怎樣可以認識我們自己呢
我們認識神
怎樣去認識神呢
去讀聖經
去崇拜
有團契的時間
祈禱的時間
我們認識神的時候
我們就understand ourselves more
We will know ourselves more
因為我們是made in God's image
我們的identity is in Christ
我們接受主耶穌
我們救主的時候
我們就recognize我們的identity
在神那裡
然後我們可以怎樣呢
我們就可以有real relationships
The next slide
就有real relationships
因為我recognize我自己是誰
我認識神的authority是什麼
我們就可以become real
我們不會很insecure
我們自己是誰
我們不會看到我們身邊的人
有judgment
We will see others as real
As God sees them
And then we can have real relationships
The next slide
我就分享我自己小時候
我做小朋友
在12、13歲的時候
我都很多時候wonder
我看到我的朋友
在high school的時候
每個人都有BFF
每個人都有best friend
我就跟神說
為什麼我沒有best friend
我一個是only child
誰是only child
我是only child的時候
有時候沒有那麼多social skill
沒有那麼多skill去跟人分享
聽別人說話
我就慢慢要學神
教我怎樣可以做一個good friend
慢慢地我就跟別人聊天
Learn how to talk with others
Share with others
關心我的朋友
And listen to他們的problems
然後神就給了我
很好的朋友
BFF
很多不同的real friend
Ok, so here are my 6 tips
towards being a real friend
第一是honesty
如果你的朋友不可以相信你
He won't be your friend
Every time他跟你說話
他以為Johnny是不是說真理
還是說謊話
He won't want to be your friend
每次都不知道你是說真的還是說假的
The first thing is honesty
The second thing is take initiative
我們要care我們的朋友
我們要主動跟他們做朋友
跟他們玩
跟他們玩遊戲機
跟他們去hang out
第三是find common points of interest
Build relationship, build trust
第四是關心我們的朋友
去care for他們,去愛他們
你有問候你的朋友
你怎樣?我聽說你之前病了
你怎樣?你的測試我聽說很難
你做得怎樣?
我們要be vulnerable
Share our struggles
之前我們要學到the right timing
有時我們會mourn
有時我們會喜樂
We need to share our struggles as well
第六是share Jesus
There is nothing greater than sharing Jesus with our friends
我有很多不同的朋友
有些是打球的朋友
有些是爬山的朋友
但最重要的是朋友可以一起祈禱
可以一起分享屬靈的東西
Spiritual的東西
我們看到怎樣去be real friend
Jesus was our ultimate example of a real friend
Jesus was honest
Jesus took initiative
Jesus connected with different people
和一個Samaritan woman
他用水去和她connect
他關心人
He healed the leper
He touched the leper
He healed the sick
Jesus was vulnerable
他和門徒說,我是很有sadness
他和門徒說,Be open, be vulnerable
然後耶穌分享了自己
This is my prayer to you
這個是我的祈禱
You will get to know God more
You will understand yourself
And become more like God
You can be a real friend like Jesus
Jesus is the real friend
耶穌是最好的朋友
他是我們的最好的例子
Let us pray
God help us to become more like you
To become a real friend
So that we can share you with others
In Christ's name we pray, Amen